export const English_Model_2012 = [
  {
    id: "h1",
    Number_of_Questions: "60 Questions",
    Time_Allowed: "1 hour",
  },
  {
    id: "h2",
    header1:
      " ADDIS ABABA CITY ADMINISTRATION EDUCATION BUREAU GRADE EIGHT MODEL EXAM ENGLISH EXAMINATION \n 2012/2020 ",
  },
  {
    id: "I",
    header1: "I. Comprehension \n Part One: Reading Passage I",
    header2:
      "Instruction: For items 1-7, read the following passage and answer the questions according to the information given in the passage.",
    // options: ["The bat", "The flying squirrel", "The bald eagle", "The colugo"],
    // correct_option: "The bat"
  },
  {
    id: "p1",
    passage:
      " Natural resources are all the things on Earth that support life. Plants, animals," +
      " air and water are natural resources. Natural resources are also things that" +
      " people use to make life easier. Your life is easier because you can ride in a bus" +
      " powered by gasoline. You can cook your dinner in a microwave oven powered" +
      " by electricity. People use natural resources to make gasoline and electricity." +
      " People use many natural resources to make their lives easier. These natural" +
      " resources have different kinds. Some natural resources are renewable, and some" +
      " resources are non renewable.",
  },
  {
    id: "p2",
    passage:
      " Renewable resources can be replaced. Plants are renewable resources. Plants" +
      " might get cut down, but they can grow back. Animals are renewable resources." +
      " They can reproduce. Solar energy is a renewable resource. Solar energy comes" +
      " from the Sun. No matter how much solar energy you use, there will always be" +
      " more. Wind, water and soil are also renewable resources.",
  },
  {
    id: "p3",
    passage:
      "  Nonrenewable resources cannot be replaced easily. Fossil fuels are" +
      " nonrenewable resources. Coal, oil and natural gas are fossil fuels. Fossil fuels" +
      " come from plants and animals that died millions of years ago. We are using up" +
      " fossil fuels much faster than Earth can replace them. Ores come from rocks" +
      " that formed millions of years ago. We use ores to make metals. Ores cannot be" +
      " replaced.",
  },
  {
    id: 1,
    question:
      "Which of the following can be the best title for the reading passage?",
    options: [
      "Renewable Resources",
      "Nonrenewable Resources",
      "Natural Resources",
      "Sources of Resources",
    ],
    correct_option: "Natural Resources",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question:
      "„… all the things on Earth that support life.‟(Paragraph 1) the word 'support'" +
      " means ____________ .",
    options: ["help", "change", "control", "manage"],
    correct_option: "help",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "The word 'powered' in paragraph 1 means ____________.",
    options: ["forced", "supplied", "added", "mechanized"],
    correct_option: "forced",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question: "What does the possessive pronoun 'their' refer in paragraph 1?",
    options: [
      "the people who use different kinds of natural resources",
      "the people who use natural resources to make lives easier",
      "the people who use natural resources to make electricity",
      "the people who use natural resources to make gasoline",
    ],
    correct_option: "the people who use different kinds of natural resources",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "The pronoun 'they' in paragraph 2 refers to __________________.",
    options: [
      "plants",
      "animals",
      "renewable resources",
      "non renewable resources",
    ],
    correct_option: "plants",
  },

  {
    id: 6,
    question:
      "According to the writer‟s point of discussion animals are categorized under" +
      " renewable resources. Because they ____________________________.",
    options: [
      "are replaceable resources",
      "can protect themselves",
      "are living together",
      "can reproduce",
    ],
    correct_option: "can reproduce",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "The writer explains in paragraph 3 about ________________.",
    options: [
      "natural resources",
      "animals and plants",
      "non renewable resources",
      "renewable resources",
    ],
    correct_option: "non renewable resources",
  },
  {
    id: "II",
    header1: "Part Two: Vocabulary",
    header2:
      "Section One: Word Underlined \n\n Instruction: For items 8-10, choose the word which has a similar meaning with the words underlined in each sentence. ",
    // options: ["The bat", "The flying squirrel", "The bald eagle", "The colugo"],
    // correct_option: "The bat"
  },

  {
    id: 8,
    question:
      'We see a frequent "fluctuation" in the weather condition of Addis Ababa, which is always changing.',
    options: ["variation", "imitation", "convention", "limitation"],
    correct_option: "variation",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question:
      'After a long reading we "realized" the main point of the content.',
    options: ["approached", "understood", "trained", "controlled"],
    correct_option: "understood",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question:
      'We must have good "discipline" in our school so that our teachers become happy.',
    options: ["image", "status", "style", "behavior"],
    correct_option: "behavior",
  },

  {
    id: "III",
    header1: "Section Two: Completion",
    header2:
      "Instruction: For items 11-13, choose the word which best completes each sentence.",
    // options: ["The bat", "The flying squirrel", "The bald eagle", "The colugo"],
    // correct_option: "The bat"
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question:
      "The soldier was terribly wounded by the explosion of a bomb in the ___________.",
    options: ["encounter", "weapon", "battle", "struggle"],
    correct_option: "battle",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question:
      "In order to take pictures, _____________ the silver button on the camera.",
    options: ["depress", "order", "compress", "press"],
    correct_option: "press",
  },
  {
    id: 13,
    question:
      "The bicycle race is being held on the city streets and _____________ must obey all the game rules.",
    options: ["supporters", "viewers", "comptitors", "athletes"],
    correct_option: "comptitors",
  },

  {
    id: "IV",
    header1: "Part Three: Sentence Comprehension",
    header2:
      "Instruction: For items 14 and 15, choose the sentence which has a similar meaning with the original sentence.",
  },
  {
    id: 14,
    question: "My only brother who lives in Jimma has got married",
    options: [
      "My brother lives in Jimma after marriage.",
      "My brother lives in Jimma with his wife.",
      "One of my brothers who lives in Jimma has got married.",
      "I have one brother who has got married and lived in Jimma",
    ],
    correct_option: "I have one brother who has got married and lived in Jimma",
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question: "Neither Dagmawit nor Nolawit is attending the class.",
    options: [
      "Dagmawit is in class but not Nolawit.",
      "Both Dagmawit and Nolawit are absent.",
      "Nolawit is absent but Dagmawit is present.",
      "Both Dagmawit and Nolawit are present.",
    ],
    correct_option: "Both Dagmawit and Nolawit are present.",
  },

  {
    id: "V",
    header1: "Part Four: Reading Passage II",
    header2:
      "Instruction: For items 16-21, read the passage carefully and choose the best answer" +
      " for each question according to the information given in the passage.",
  },
  {
    id: "p4",
    passage:
      "Good manners are one of those things people appreciate. Politeness, honesty and" +
      " others are highly admired. I think in Ethiopia one of the good manners that is" +
      " highly appreciated is respect. Elders play a very important role in the Ethiopian" +
      "society; in fact they are mediators on every issue ranging from business, family" +
      "issues and even in times of national issues.",
  },
  {
    id: "p5",
    passage:
      " Elders play the role of judges. When a married couple is facing difficult" +
      " material issues, elders come in and try to solve the situation and create peace. I" +
      " think, this role that elders have played for a long time mainly rest on the fact that" +
      " they have power, in society. But lately, meaning the past few decades, I hear" +
      " of less and less “shimigilina,” i.e mediation by elders and more of mediation" +
      " by judges. Married couples go to judges instead of calling their elders to help" +
      "them solve the problems",
  },
  {
    id: "p6",
    passage:
      " Not all elders are wise, considerate and just, not all are capable of resolving" +
      " disputes and not all are interested in being involved in such processes. And in" +
      " some cases, some elders are so unfriendly and rude. But there is a traditional" +
      " role that they have played. Unfortunately, our understanding and respect for" +
      " tradition seems to be on a downward move. We seem to drop all that is" +
      "traditional.",
  },

  {
    id: 16,
    question:
      " According to the writer, what is the good manner that is highly appreciated in Ethiopia?",
    options: ["honestly", "impoliteness", "respect", "politeness"],
    correct_option: "respect",
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question:
      "...in fact they are mediators on every issue… (Paragraph 1), they refers to",
    options: ["people", "society", "elder", "family"],
    correct_option: "elder",
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question:
      "Which of the following statements is NOT true according to paragraph 3?",
    options: [
      "Not all elders are wise",
      "Some elders are not friendly.",
      "All elders are able to resolve problems.",
      "We are not developing our tradition.",
    ],
    correct_option: "All elders are able to resolve problems.",
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question:
      "The word 'mediation' in paragraph 2 means ________________________.",
    options: [
      "ending disagreement",
      "beginning disagreement",
      "problem",
      "dispute",
    ],
    correct_option: "ending disagreement",
  },
  {
    id: 20,
    question: "What is the concluding idea of paragraph 2?",
    options: [
      "Judges play the role of elders.",
      "Elders can resolve problems in the society.",
      "Wealthy people in the society are elders.",
      "Elders are unable to give solutions.",
    ],
    correct_option: "Elders can resolve problems in the society.",
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question:
      "The fact that elders solve marriage problems and play the role of judges mainly" +
      " because they ___________________________.",
    options: [
      "are educated",
      "have power in society",
      "have judge power",
      "are famous",
    ],
    correct_option: "have power in society",
  },

  {
    id: "VI",
    header1: "II. Language Focus/Grammar",
    header2:
      "Instruction: For items 22-47, choose the one that best completes each sentence.",
  },
  {
    id: 22,
    question:
      "Machines manipulate works that humans can‟t. They ____________ lift objects that weigh many tons",
    options: ["would", "must", "should", "can"],
    correct_option: "can",
    explanation:
      "Modal verbs are used along with a main verb to indicate ability, necessity, possibility, and permission" +
      "Can	Indicate ability or possibility,Would	Past form of “will” and used to Make a polite request,Should	Make a suggestion" +
      "Must	Indicate obligation",
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question:
      "In Ethiopia, the victory of „Adwa‟ is commemorated____________________ in the month of February.",
    options: ["every year", "every day", "every month", "every week"],
    correct_option: "every year",
    explanation:
      'The phrase "every year" indicates that the commemoration of the victory of "Adwa" happens annually.',
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question: "____________________ your gold necklace with that dress.",
    options: ["Wearing", "Wore", "Wears", "Wear"],
    correct_option: "Wear",
    explanation:
      'The word "Wear" in this context is used as a command or suggestion to indicate what action should be taken with regard to the gold necklace and the dress.' +
      "It suggests that the person should put on or use their gold necklace together with the mentioned dress.",
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question:
      "The chairperson requested me, ________________________ people came to the party?",
    options: ["how long", "how much", "how far", "how many"],
    correct_option: "how many",
    explanation:
      "we use 'how much' with uncountable nouns. These nouns are always singular and they cannot be counted." +
      "'How many,is when the noun we are talking about is countable and has a plural form.",
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question: "Have you __________________________ doing your assignment?",
    options: ["finished", "finishing", "finish", "finishes"],
    correct_option: "finishes",
    explanation:
      'The word "finished" is the past participle form of the verb "finish" ' +
      ' In this sentence, the auxiliary verb "have" is used to form the present perfect tense.' +
      "  When forming the present perfect tense, we use the past participle form of the main verb." +
      'Therefore, "finished" is the correct form to use in this context.',
  },
  {
    id: 27,
    question:
      "The director often ___________________________ us instructions about the" +
      " school rules and regulations.",
    options: ["is given", "was given", "gives", "give"],
    correct_option: "gives",
    explanation:
      'The verb "gives" is the correct option because it matches the subject "director" and agrees with the present tense of the sentence.' +
      "In this context, the sentence is describing a habitual action or a routine activity that the director performs regularly.",
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question:
      "There are many ways of HIV/AIDS transmission. Hence, we ____________share" +
      " razors and syringes with people.",
    options: ["can‟t", "mustn‟t", "need to", "ought to"],
    correct_option: "ought to",
    explanation:
      `The word "mustn't" is used to express prohibition or to indicate that something is not allowed.` +
      " In this context, the sentence is emphasizing the importance of not sharing razors and syringes with others due to the risk of HIV/AIDS transmission." +
      ` "Mustn't" conveys a strong sense of obligation or necessity not to engage in the specified action for safety and health reasons.`,
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question: " ______________ your father drive a red car?",
    options: ["Was", "Does", "Do", "Is"],
    correct_option: "Is",
    explanation:
      'The word "Does" is used in questions when forming present simple questions with third-person singular subjects, such as "he", "she", "it", or singular nouns.' +
      ` In this context, the question is asking about a habitual action or fact related to the speaker's father, so "Does" is the appropriate word to initiate the question.`,
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question: "This is a decision I have __________ made once.",
    options: ["still", "till", "yet", "already"],
    correct_option: "already",
    explanation:
      "“Still” is used to say that something is continuing and has not stopped:" +
      " “Yet” is used to talk about something that is expected; " +
      " “Already” is used to say that something has happened early, or earlier than it might have happened.",
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question:
      "It rained heavily ____________________we were watching a football match.",
    options: ["while", "then", "so", "as"],
    correct_option: "as",
    explanation:
      '"As" is used to indicate a simultaneous action or event.' +
      " In this context, it suggests that the heavy rain occurred at the same time as the football match was being watched.",
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    question:
      "Our father ___________________ take us to Hawasa for a visit on the coming 30th of July",
    options: ["is going to", "was going to ", "had going to", "has going to"],
    correct_option: "Is going to",
    explanation:
      '"Is going to" is the present continuous form used to talk about future arrangements or plans that have already been made.' +
      "In this sentence, it indicates that the action of taking the speaker and others to Hawasa on the 30th of July is a planned event.",
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    question:
      " I think ____________ the students will answer this question correctly since it is very easy",
    options: ["more of", "most of", "much of", "none of"],
    correct_option: "Most of",
    explanation:
      '"Most of" is used to indicate a majority or a large portion of a group.' +
      "In this context, it suggests that the speaker believes a large number of the students will answer the question correctly because it is very easy.",
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    question: "The hotel __________________ its delicious food.",
    options: ["is famous", "is famous for", "famous for", "famous"],
    correct_option: "famous",
    explanation:
      'Is famous for" is the appropriate phrase to indicate what the hotel is known for.' +
      ' is famous for" correctly connects the subject "the hotel" with the reason for its fame, which is its delicious food.',
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    question:
      "The school ______________ he thought was too far from the city center.",
    options: ["where", "what", "when", "who"],
    correct_option: "where",
    explanation:
      '"Which" is used to introduce a relative clause that provides additional information about a noun.' +
      'In this context, it connects the relative clause "he thought was too far from the city center" to the noun "school" ' +
      " indicating the specific school about which he had a particular thought." +
      '"Where" is not the correct option in this context because "where" is typically used to refer to a place or location,' +
      "not to introduce a clause describing the characteristics or qualities of a noun. In this sentence, we are describing the school itself, not its location. ",
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    question: "Look! Tolosa is _____________ handsome than his elder brother.",
    options: ["most", "little", "least", "less"],
    correct_option: "less",
    explanation:
      "In the sentence, we are comparing the handsomeness of Tolosa to his elder brother." +
      ' Since "Tolosa" and "his elder brother" are only two individuals being compared,' +
      ' we use the comparative form "less" to indicate that Tolosa is not as handsome as his elder brother.',
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    question:
      "Ethiopian Airlines __________________ a new dream liner airplane last year.",
    options: ["buy", "bought", "is bought", "was buying"],
    correct_option: "bought",
    explanation:
      "The sentence is referring to an action that occurred in the past, specifically last year." +
      'Therefore, the correct verb form to use is the past tense "bought, " indicating that Ethiopian Airlines purchased a new dream liner airplane last year.',
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question:
      "Mastewal has scored high in the examination; _________________, the" +
      " school allowed her a free education for her next study. ",
    options: ["as a result", "even though", "whenever", "where as"],
    correct_option: "as a result",
    explanation:
      'The phrase " as a result" indicates a consequence or outcome of a previous action or event.' +
      ` In this context, Mastewal's high score in the examination led to the school allowing her to receive free education for her next study.`,
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question:
      "I would like to take you to a cafe _______________ serves excellent coffee.",
    options: ["what", "which", "who", "where"],
    correct_option: "where",
    explanation:
      'In this context, "which" is used to introduce a relative clause that provides additional information about the cafe.' +
      " The relative clause describes the quality of the cafe, stating that it serves excellent coffee.",
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    question: "_____________ trees are planted, the rain won‟t erode the soil.",
    options: ["What ", "When", "While ", "How"],
    correct_option: "When",
    explanation:
      '"When" is used to indicate a condition or circumstance in which something happens.' +
      "In this context, it suggests that planting trees is the condition that prevents soil erosion by rain.",
  },
  {
    id: 41,
    question:
      "The food I ate at the restaurant was too cheap _____________ it was so delicious.",
    options: ["for", "but", "so", "or"],
    correct_option: "but",
    explanation:
      'The word "but" is used to contrast two clauses or ideas.' +
      " In this context, it indicates a contrast between the low price of the food and its deliciousness.",
  },
  {
    id: 42,
    question:
      "They went shopping in the morning and _____________they returned to home.",
    options: ["then", "first", "finally", "next"],
    correct_option: "then",
    explanation:
      '"Then" is often used to indicate a chronological sequence of events,',
  },
  {
    id: 43,
    question:
      "The students _______________________ that the final examination would be" +
      "given at the end of April.",
    options: ["were informed", "was informed", "is informed", "are informed"],
    correct_option: "were informed",
    explanation:
      'The correct form of the verb is "were informed"' +
      'because "students" is a plural noun, requiring the plural form of the verb "to be, " which is "were."',
  },
  {
    id: 44,
    question: "He was still hungry _______________ he had eaten a large meal.",
    options: ["unless", "because", "although", "since"],
    correct_option: "although",
    explanation:
      'The correct option is "although" It expresses the idea that despite having eaten a large meal, he was still hungry.',
  },
  {
    id: 45,
    question:
      " There were not enough beds in your house, __________________ I had to sleep on the sofa.",
    options: ["so", "but", "or", "and"],
    correct_option: "so",
    explanation:
      'The correct option is "so." It indicates the reason for sleeping on the sofa, implying that there were not enough beds available.',
  },
  {
    id: 46,
    question:
      "We planned to buy a mobile, so we should stop shopping now _______________ we spend all our money.",
    options: ["after", "before", "next", "finally"],
    correct_option: "before",
    explanation:
      'The word "before" in this context suggests a sense of urgency or necessity to act preemptively.' +
      " It implies that the action of stopping shopping should occur prior to spending all the money.",
  },
  {
    id: 47,
    question:
      "The reported form of the statement '' I like ice cream.'' is __________________.  ",
    options: [
      "He said that he has liked ice cream",
      "He said that he is liking ice cream",
      "He said that he liked ice cream",
      "He said that he was liking ice cream",
    ],
    correct_option: "He said that he liked ice cream",
    explanation:
      'The reported form of the statement "I like ice cream." is "He said that he liked ice cream."',
  },

  {
    id: "IIV",
    header1: "III. Speaking",
    header2:
      "Instruction: For items 48-53, choose the one which is the best expression to complete the missing part of the dialogue.",
  },
  {
    id: 48,
    question:
      "Robel:  Have you ever eaten a burger in this restaurant?\n Getu:  ____________________.",
    options: ["Yes, I ever", "Yes, I do", "Yes, I have", "Yes, I had"],
    correct_option: "Yes, I have",
    explanation:
      'The correct response uses the present perfect tense ("Yes, I have") because it refers to an experience that started in the past (eating a burger)' +
      " and has relevance to the present moment.",
  },
  {
    id: 49,
    question:
      "Rahel: ________________________________? \n" +
      "Zinash:  I wore a new white dress with a red border and matching shawl.",
    options: [
      "What did your sister wear for a holiday",
      "Did you receive clothes from friends as a gift",
      "What were you wearing for the past holiday",
      "What are you wearing to celebrate the holiday",
    ],
    correct_option: "What were you wearing for the past holiday",
    explanation:
      `The question "What were you wearing for the past holiday?" asks about Rahel's attire during a previous holiday,` +
      " which matches the context of Zinash's response describing what she wore during a past holiday.",
  },
  {
    id: 50,
    question:
      ". Abrehet:  What is the best way of learning? \n" +
      "Kalkidan:  ___________________________.",
    options: [
      "I have no words to say just find your way of learning",
      "You must learn math, science and other subjects as best way",
      "I think students learning together should be polite with each other",
      "I think working in pairs or small groups may help you to learn best",
    ],
    correct_option:
      "I think working in pairs or small groups may help you to learn best",
    explanation:
      "It directly addresses Abrehet's question about the best way of learning by suggesting collaborative learning methods.",
  },
  {
    id: 51,
    question:
      "Ayenachew:  Do you have extra pen please! \n" +
      "Tamralech:  ____________. Here it is.",
    options: ["Yes, I do", "Yes, I have", "No, I don't", "No, I haven‟t"],
    correct_option: "Yes, I do.",
    explanation:
      '"Yes, I do." This indicates that Tamralech does indeed have an extra pen.',
  },
  {
    id: 52,
    question:
      " Salhadin:  I think Salah is the best player of English premier league this season. Do you? \n" +
      "Oumed:  _____________. I think Kane is the best of all.",
    options: [
      "you can‟t think like that",
      "I am afraid I haven't",
      "please, don‟t ask me",
      "I am afraid I disagree",
    ],
    correct_option: "I am afraid I disagree",
    explanation:
      "This indicates Oumed's disagreement with Salhadin's opinion about Salah being the best player," +
      "expressing his belief that Kane is the best instead.",
  },
  {
    id: 53,
    question:
      "Samrawit:What sport do you think is the most dangerous? \n" +
      "Elfinesh: _____________________.",
    options: [
      "I can play volleyball",
      "In my opinion basketball",
      " I don't like sport",
      "Football is my favorite",
    ],
    correct_option: "In my opinion basketball",
    explanation:
      "This indicates Elfinesh's opinion about basketball being the most dangerous sport.",
  },

  {
    id: "IIIV",
    header1: "IV. Writing",
    header2:
      "Section One: Jumbled Words \n\n" +
      "Instruction: Items 54 and 55 contain jumbled words. Choose the one which has a" +
      " correct sequence or arrangement to make a meaningful sentence.",
  },
  {
    id: 54,
    question: "brother / in/ my /a / little / government / school / learns",
    options: [
      "My little brother in a school learns government.",
      "My little brother learns in a government school.",
      "My little brother learns a government in school.",
      "My little brother learns a school in government.",
    ],
    correct_option: "My little brother learns a school in government.",
    explanation: "",
  },
  {
    id: 55,
    question: "any / Ethiopians / you / know / do / famous",
    options: [
      "Do you any famous Ethiopians know?",
      "Do any famous you Ethiopians know?",
      "Do you know any famous Ethiopians?",
      "Do you know Ethiopians any famous?",
    ],
    correct_option: "Do you know any famous Ethiopians?",
    explanation: "",
  },

  {
    id: "IX",
    header1: "Section Two: Jumbled Sentences",
    header2:
      "Instruction: For item 56, the given sentences 1-4 are not in the correct order; read" +
      " the sentences carefully and choose the appropriate order of the sentences to make a" +
      " meaningful paragraph.",
  },
  {
    id: 56,
    question:
      " 1. Both have plants and animals living in them. \n" +
      "2. However, lakes are much smaller bodies of fresh water. \n" +
      "3. Oceans and lakes have similarities and differences. \n" +
      "4. Oceans are very large bodies of salt water",
    options: ["1, 2, 3, 4 ", "2, 1, 4, 3 ", "3, 2, 1, 4", "3, 1, 4, 2"],
    correct_option: "3, 2, 1, 4",
    explanation: "",
  },
  {
    id: "X",
    header1: "Section Three: Punctuation and Capitalization",
    header2:
      "Instruction:For items 57-59, choose the sentence which is correctly punctuated and capitalized.",
  },
  {
    id: 57,
    question: "",
    options: [
      "I need to buy chocolate, banana, and orange for my birthday party.",
      " I need to buy chocolate, banana and orange for my birthday party.",
      "I need to buy, chocolate, banana and orange for my birthday party.",
      "I need to buy chocolate, banana, and, orange for my birthday party.",
    ],
    correct_option:
      "I need to buy chocolate, banana, and, orange for my birthday party.",
    explanation: "",
  },
  {
    id: 58,
    question: "",
    options: [
      "Selamawit's and Abdurehman's bags are exactly alike.",
      "Selamawits and Abdurehmans bags are exactly alike.",
      "Selamawit's and Abdurehman bags are exactly alike.",
      "Selamawit and Abdurehman's bags are exactly alike.",
    ],
    correct_option: "Selamawit and Abdurehman's bags are exactly alike",
    explanation:
      "The correct sentence follows the rule for possessive forms of nouns." +
      " When two or more people possess something jointly, the possessive marker ('s) is added only to the last name." +
      ` So, in this case, "Selamawit and Abdurehman" is treated as a unit, and the possessive marker ('s) is added to the last name,` +
      ` "Abdurehman, " indicating that both individuals share ownership of the bags. ` +
      "Additionally, the sentence is properly capitalized at the beginning and ends with a period, adhering to standard punctuation rules.",
  },
  {
    id: 59,
    question: "",
    options: [
      "The tutorial will be given to all students on mondays, wednesdays and Fridays.",
      "The tutorial will be given to all students on mondays, wednesdays and fridays.",
      "The tutorial will be given to all students on Mondays, Wednesdays and Fridays",
      "The tutorial will be given to all students on Mondays, wednesdays and fridays.",
    ],
    correct_option:
      "The tutorial will be given to all students on Mondays, wednesdays and fridays.",
    explanation:
      "Based on correct capitalization and punctuation rules, the correct option is:" +
      ` "The tutorial will be given to all students on Mondays, Wednesdays, and Fridays."`,
  },

  {
    id: "XI",
    header1: "Section Four: Spelling",
    header2:
      "Instruction:For items 60, choose the world which in correct spelling",
  },
  {
    id: 60,
    question: "",
    options: ["poplation", "poplasion", "population", "populadhion"],
    correct_option: "population",
    explanation: "",
  },
];



export const English_Model_2016 = [
  {
    id: "h1",
    Number_of_Questions: "60 Questions",
    Time_Allowed: "1 hour",
  },
  {
    id: "h2",
    header1:
      " ADDIS ABABA CITY ADMINISTRATION EDUCATION BUREAU GRADE EIGHT MODEL EXAM ENGLISH EXAMINATION \n 2016E.C (2024)",
  },
  {
    id: "I",
    header1: "I. Comprehension \n Part One: Reading Passage",
    header2:
      "Instruction: For items 1-7, read the following passage and answer the questions according to the information given in the passage.",
    // options: ["The bat", "The flying squirrel", "The bald eagle", "The colugo"],
    // correct_option: "The bat"
  },
  {
    id: "two",
    header1: "'PART ONE: READING'",
    header2: "Ethiopian Endemic Animal, Bale Monkey",
  },
  {
    id: "three",
    passage:
      "The Bale monkey also known as the Bale mountains grivet, Bale mountains vervet, and Djam-djam,is" +
      "endemic to the highlands of Ethiopia and found east of the Rift Valley in the Bale Mountains and" +
      "Sidamo Highlands. It is one of six species in the genus Chlorocebus, but it is unique among them in" +
      "having a very restricted distribution and specialized habitat. \n" +
      "Bale monkeys living in bamboo forests are primarily arboreal, spending most of their time in the trees" +
      "and only rarely descending to the ground. However, populations living in forest fragments, where much" +
      "of the bamboo has been eradicated, spend more time traveling and foraging on the ground." +
      "There is some sexual dimorphism in this species; males weigh up to 6.4 kg while females weigh up to" +
      "4.9 kg. Combined head and body length measures about 42–60 cm for males and 30–50 cm for females." +
      "The Bale monkey's tail is distinctly shorter than the closely related grivet or vervet monkey at around" +
      "46–76 cm in males, and 41–66 cm in females. Since they are less studied than other primates, the" +
      "average lifespan of this species in not known, although similar species can live to be around 25 years" +
      "old. However very little is known about reproduction in the Bale monkey, infants are generally weaned" +
      "by about 6 months of age and usually reach sexual maturity at around 4–5 years of age. \n" +
      "The Bale monkey has greyish-brown coat, with some yellow and red tones, particularly on the top of" +
      "the head. This pelage turns white on the underside of their torso, arms, and legs. Their dark faces are" +
      "framed on either side by fluffy white whiskers, giving them the impression of having a white beard and" +
      "moustache. Their hands, feet, and ears are all a blackish-brown. Having these let them look quite" +
      "similar to their close relatives, the vervet monkey and grivet, but can be distinguished by their shorter" +
      "tail, shorter facial whiskers, and barely visible white brow. \n" +
      "As well as living in a specialized habitat, Bale monkeys also have a highly specialized diet. The" +
      "majority of the Bale monkey's diet comes from just one plant: bamboo. The young leaves of bamboo" +
      "account for over 75% of the food consumed by Bale monkeys. The rest of their diet generally consists" +
      "of plant matter from just a handful of other species, although they do sometimes eat small animals. Bale" +
      "monkeys spend the majority of their time feeding and moving, and only a relatively small amount of" +
      "time resting or engaging in social activities. In the wet season, they spend more time feeding than" +
      "during the dry season. They are a diurnal species, sleeping during the day, and traveling approximately" +
      "0.62 miles (1 km) each day. Unfortunately, at several human-dominated sites, Bale monkeys have lost" +
      "much of their natural diet of bamboo through deforestation. To supplement their diet, they engage in" +
      "crop-feeding; Bale monkeys have been known to feed on barley, other cereals, vegetables, and fruit that" +
      "are grown by local farmers. This results human-wildlife conflict that has led to the hunting and trapping" +
      "of these monkeys by farmers. (Adapted from Wikipedia)",
  },
  {
    id: 1,
    question: "What is the other name of Bale monkey?",
    options: [
      "Bale mountain goat",
      "Bale mountain ape",
      "Bale mountain grivet",
      "North Rift Valley Djam-djam",
    ],
    correct_option: "Bale mountain grivet",
  },
  {
    id: 2,
    question:
      "According to paragraph 1, why are Bale monkeys unique from others Chlorocebus genus?",
    options: [
      "They have restricted distribution and specialized habitat.",
      "They are only the species of Chlorocebus genus.",
      "They are only animals which live in bamboo forests.",
      " They aren't the species of Chlorocebus genus.",
    ],
    correct_option:
      "They have restricted distribution and specialized habitat.",
  },
  {
    id: 3,
    question: "Which one of the followings is TRUE about paragraph 3?",
    options: [
      "Female Bale monkeys are more weighed than males.",
      "Male Bale monkeys are taller than males.",
      "Male Bale monkeys are less weighed than females.",
      "Female Bale monkeys are taller than males.",
    ],
    correct_option: "Male Bale monkeys are less weighed than females",
  },
  {
    id: 4,
    question:
      "According to paragraph 4, which one of the followings doesn't describe the physical appearance of these animals?",
    options: [
      "They have greenish-brown coat.",
      "They have greyish-brown coat.",
      "they have blackish-brown hands, feet, and ears.",
      "They have yellow and red tones.",
    ],
    correct_option: "They have greenish-brown coat.",
  },
  {
    id: 5,
    question: "The majority of Bale mountain comes from,",
    options: [
      "young leaves barley",
      "fruits",
      "young leaves bamboo",
      "cereals",
    ],
    correct_option: "young leaves bamboo",
  },
  {
    id: 6,
    question:
      "Why are these monkeys hunted and trapped by farmers? Because they",
    options: [
      "aattack and kill people of the area",
      "are wanted in local market.",
      "feed on crops that are grown by local farmers.",
      "are required for their furs and skins",
    ],
    correct_option: "feed on crops that are grown by local farmers",
  },
  {
    id: 7,
    question: "What does ‘their' in paragraph 2 refer to?",
    options: [
      "Bamboo forests",
      "Highlands of Ethiopia",
      "Bale monkeys",
      "Bale farmers",
    ],
    correct_option: "Bale monkeys",
  },

  {
    id: 8,
    question: "What does ‘these' in paragraph 4 refer to?",
    options: [
      "Bale monkeys",
      "farmers' barley, vegetables, and fruits",
      "Bale monkeys' specialized diet",
      "Monkeys' blackish-brown hands, feet, and ears",
    ],
    correct_option: "Bale monkeys' specialized diet",
  },
  {
    id: 9,
    question: "What does ‘consumed' in (paragraph 5 line 2) mean?",
    options: ["provided", "prepared", "distributed", "eaten up"],
    correct_option: "eaten up ",
  },
  {
    id: 10,
    question: "What does endemic in (paragraph 1 line 2) mean?",
    options: [
      "particular to the place",
      "widespread",
      "pandemic",
      "found everywhere",
    ],
    correct_option: "particular to the place ",
  },

  {
    id: "II",
    header1: "Section Two: Sentence Comprehension",
    header2:
      "Instruction: For questions 11 and 12 choose the alternatives that are similar or nearly similar to the original one.",
    // options: ["The bat", "The flying squirrel", "The bald eagle", "The colugo"],
    // correct_option: "The bat"
  },
  {
    id: 11,
    question: "I prefer drinking milk to eating cake.",
    options: [
      "I prefer drinking milk and eating cake.",
      "I don't prefer drinking milk and eating cake.",
      "I prefer drinking milk, not eating cake",
      "I prefer eating cake, not drinking milk.",
    ],
    correct_option: "I prefer eating cake, not drinking milk.",
    explanation:
      '"I prefer drinking milk to eating cake." This sentence indicates a preference for one action over another. The correct option, "I prefer eating cake, not drinking milk, ' +
      " properly contrasts the preference by stating a preference for eating cake instead of drinking milk",
  },
  {
    id: 12,
    question: " A cupboard is too heavy to lift up.",
    options: [
      "It is difficult to lift up a cupboard.",
      " You can easily move a cupboard everywhere.",
      " It is very simple to displace a cupboard.",
      " Anyone can carry the cupboard.",
    ],
    correct_option: "It is difficult to lift up a cupboard.",
    explanation:
      "This sentence expresses the difficulty of lifting a cupboard due to its weight. The correct option," +
      '"It is difficult to lift up a cupboard, " provides an explanation for why the cupboard is heavy to lift, emphasizing the challenging nature of the task.',
  },
  {
    id: "IV",
    header1: "PART TWO: VOCABULARY",
    header2:
      "Instruction One: For the questions 13-17, choose the most similar meaning of the bold and underlined words in the following sentences.",
  },

  {
    id: 13,
    question:
      " Rural non-farm activities are very essential for generating income.",
    options: [" tiresome ", " unnecessary ", "vital ", " disadvantageous "],
    correct_option: "vital",
  },

  {
    id: 14,
    question:
      " The Ethiopian calendar regulates the ceremonial cycle of national holidays.",
    options: ["ignores", " isolates", " discriminates ", "controls"],
    correct_option: "controls",
    explanation:
      'The word "essential" indicates that these activities are important or necessary. Among the options provided,' +
      ' "vital" is the most similar in meaning, as it also conveys a sense of importance or necessity.',
  },
  {
    id: 15,
    question:
      " Minilik's Bushbucks are forest living animals inhabiting dense bush.",
    options: ["escaping", "dwelling", " migrating ", "constructing"],
    correct_option: "dwelling",
    explanation:
      'The phrase "inhabiting dense bush" implies that the animals dwell or live in such environments.' +
      'Therefore, the word "dwelling" is the most similar in meaning.',
  },
  {
    id: 16,
    question:
      "Cows are raised by farmers for they provide milk and milk products.",
    Options: ["prohibit", "give", "protect", "disallow"],
    correct_option: "give",
    explanation:
      'The phrase "for they provide" indicates that cows are raised because they give or provide milk and milk products.' +
      ' Among the options, "give" best represents this idea of providing something.',
  },
  {
    id: 17,
    question:
      "Road traffic accidents are serious, but neglected health problems in Ethiopia.",
    options: ["ignored", " difficult ", " different ", "cleared "],
    correct_option: "ignored",
    explanation:
      'The word "neglected" suggests that road traffic accidents are serious health problems that have not received enough attention or care. ',
  },
  {
    id: 18,
    question: " I concentrate on my lesson and learning",
    options: ["read ", " entertain", "clean ", "focus"],
    correct_option: "focus",
    explanation: `The word "concentrate" suggests focusing one's attention or mental effort on something.`,
  },
  {
    id: 19,
    question:
      " Corona virus causes devastating effect on the economy of Ethiopia. ",
    options: ["destroying ", "causing ", " supporting ", " increasing "],
    correct_option: "causing",
    explanation: `The word "causes" indicates that the coronavirus leads to or brings about devastating effects on the economy.`,
  },
  {
    header1: "Section Two: Sentence Comprehension",
    header2:
      "Instruction: For questions 20-26, choose the best word that completes the following sentences from the given alternatives.",
    // options: ["The bat", "The flying squirrel", "The bald eagle", "The colugo"],
    // correct_option: "The bat"
  },

  {
    id: 20,
    question:
      "My father is ____________ person; he does everything in concentration.",
    options: ["careful ", "forgetful", "reluctant ", "absent minded"],
    correct_option: "careful",
    explanation:
      ' The word "careful" fits the context as it describes someone who pays attention to detail and exercises caution. ' +
      ' It contrasts with options like "forgetful, " "reluctant, " and "absent - minded, " which do not convey the same sense of attentiveness.',
  },
  {
    id: 21,
    question:
      " Hyenas are ___________ animals which mostly move during the night.",
    options: ["day active ", "nocturnal ", " day loving ", " diurnal "],
    correct_option: "nocturnal",
    explanation:
      'The word "nocturnal" describes animals that are active at night.' +
      'Among the options, "nocturnal" best fits the description provided in the sentence.',
  },

  {
    id: 22,
    question:
      "The number of Ethiopian wolves becomes _______ because of indiscriminate shooting by hunters.",
    options: ["Exceeding ", " maximizing ", "reducing", " increasing "],
    correct_option: "reducing",
    explanation:
      'The word "reducing" indicates a decrease in the number of Ethiopian wolves.' +
      ' Options like "exceeding, " "maximizing, " and "increasing" do not convey the intended meaning of decreasing.',
  },
  {
    id: 23,
    question:
      "Driving after drinking much alcohol is _________ to _________ traffic accident",
    options: [
      "forbidden/encourage",
      "prohibited/preven",
      "allowed/protect",
      "appreciated/ promote",
    ],
    correct_option: "prohibited/prevent",
    explanation:
      'The phrase "prohibited/ prevent" correctly conveys that driving after drinking alcohol is not allowed and helps prevent traffic accidents.',
  },
  {
    id: 24,
    question:
      "Abel has ______ behaviour in his family. He is cool and calm while his siblings are naughty and undisciplined.",
    options: ["distinct ", " alike", "identical", "similar"],
    correct_option: "distinct",
    explanation:
      `The word "distinct" suggests that Abel's behavior is different or unique compared to that of his siblings.` +
      `Options like "alike, " "identical, " and "similar" imply similarity, which contradicts the sentence's meaning.`,
  },
  {
    id: 25,
    question:
      " The people of the area cut lot of trees per day. This leads to __________ ",
    options: ["Afforestation ", " replanting ", "deforestation ", " rainfall"],
    correct_option: "deforestation",
    explanation:
      'The word "deforestation" refers to the clearing or removal of trees on a large scale.' +
      " It directly correlates with the context provided in the sentence.",
  },
  {
    id: 26,
    question:
      " _____________ is the preservation threatened wildlife habitats.",
    options: ["Conservation", " Disappearance", " Extinction", " Murdering"],
    correct_option: "Conservation",
    explanation:
      "Conservation refers to the protection, preservation, and management of natural resources," +
      "including wildlife habitats, to prevent their degradation or destruction.",
  },
  {
    id: "V",
    header1: "PART Three: GRAMMAR",
    header2:
      "Instruction: Choose the correct answer for the questions 27-48 from the given alternative based of grammatical usage.",
  },

  {
    id: 27,
    question: "The letter ________ to Tesfaye by his brother every Sunday.",
    options: ["is send ", "are send", "is sent", "are sent"],
    correct_option: "is sent",
    explanation:
      'The correct option is "is sent." This is because "letter" is a singular noun,' +
      'so the correct verb form to use with it is "is sent."',
  },
  {
    id: 28,
    question:
      'What is the passive form of "They sometimes seek him to entertain them."?',
    options: [
      "They are sometimes sought by him to entertain them. ",
      "They are sometimes seek by him to entertain them.",
      "He is sometimes seek by them to entertain them ",
      "He is sometimes sought by them to entertain them.",
    ],
    correct_option: "He is sometimes sought by them to entertain them.",
    explanation:
      'In the original sentence "They sometimes seek him to entertain them, " the subject "They" performs the action "seek."' +
      ' In the passive voice, the subject becomes the recipient of the action, while the agent (the one performing the action) is optionally included using "by."' +
      ' Therefore, in the passive form, "They" becomes "He, " and "seek" becomes "sought."',
  },
  {
    id: 29,
    question:
      "Obse is _____________ Kidist because it is difficult to distinguish their difference ",
    options: [
      "more gorgeous ",
      " as gorgeous as ",
      "not as gorgeous as",
      " the most gorgeous ",
    ],
    correct_option: "not as gorgeous as",
    explanation:
      'The word " as " in the sentence indicates a comparison of the two individuals, Obse and Kidist.' +
      ' "As gorgeous as " is a comparative phrase used to indicate that both Obse and Kidist possess a similar level of beauty.' +
      " Therefore, the sentence suggests that Obse is equally beautiful as Kidist.",
  },
  {
    id: 30,
    question: " Right now, the experiments______________ by scientists.",
    options: [
      "are being investigated",
      " are investigated",
      " are investigating ",
      " are being investigating",
    ],
    correct_option: "are being investigated",
    explanation:
      "This sentence is in the present continuous passive voice, indicating that the experiments are currently undergoing investigation by scientists." +
      ' The passive voice is formed with the auxiliary verb "are" followed by the present participle "being" and the past participle "investigated."' +
      ' Therefore, the correct option is "are being investigated."',
  },
  {
    id: 31,
    question:
      'What is the active form of "Vegetables are bought by her every day."?',
    options: [
      "She buy vegetables every day.",
      " She buys vegetables every day ",
      " Vegetables buy by her every day.",
      " Vegetables buy her every day",
    ],
    correct_option: "She buys vegetables every day.",
    explanation:
      " To convert a passive voice sentence to active voice," +
      " we typically make the subject of the passive sentence the agent of the active sentence and change the verb form accordingly. ",
  },
  {
    id: 32,
    question: "Which one of the following sentences is ODD based on it voice? ",
    options: [
      "We learn about simple present passive.",
      " Our teacher teaches us about simple present tense passive.",
      " We are taught about simple present passive.",
      " We are learning about simple present passive.",
    ],
    correct_option: "We learn about simple present passive.",
    explanation:
      'The sentence "We learn about simple present passive." is odd because it is in the active voice, whereas the other sentences are in the passive voice.',
  },
  {
    id: 33,
    question: " Walia Ibex has ____________ horns than mountain Nyala.",
    options: ["large", "larger", "the largest ", "as large as "],
    correct_option: "larger",
    explanation:
      'Comparing the horns of two animals, "larger" is the appropriate term to indicate that the horns of the Walia Ibex are bigger than those of the mountain Nyala.',
  },
  {
    id: 34,
    question: " You _______ to pay tax if you own car.",
    options: ["should ", "must", " can ", " have "],
    correct_option: "must",
    explanation:
      '"Must" is used to express obligation or necessity.' +
      " In this sentence, it indicates that paying tax is a requirement or obligation for someone who owns a car.",
  },
  {
    id: 35,
    question: " The food in that restaurant was the ……………. I had ever eaten.",
    options: ["Best", " better", " worse", "good "],
    correct_option: "Best",
    explanation:
      "The sentence is comparing the food in the restaurant to other food experiences." +
      ' "Best" is the superlative form of the adjective "good, " indicating the highest level of quality among all the food the speaker has ever eaten.',
  },
  {
    id: 36,
    question:
      "The more confident you are the __________________ person you become.",
    options: [
      "convincinger",
      "convincing ",
      "more convincing",
      " convincingest ",
    ],
    correct_option: "more convincing",
    explanation:
      'The correct option is "more convincing." In comparative forms, the word "more" is used to indicate a higher degree of the adjective, so in this case,' +
      ' it would be "more convincing" to indicate increasing levels of persuasiveness as confidence increases.',
  },
  {
    id: 37,
    question: " What is the comparative form of ‘ill'?",
    options: ["iller", " worst ", " more ill ", "worse"],
    correct_option: "worse",
    explanation: ' In the comparative form, "ill" becomes "worse."',
  },
  {
    id: 38,
    question: " She makes cakes every Sunday. The passive form is ----------",
    options: [
      "Every Sunday cakes made by her.",
      "Cakes were made by her every Sunday.",
      " Cakes make her every Sunday.",
      " Cakes are made by her every sun day. ",
    ],
    correct_option: "Cakes were made by her every Sunday.",
    explanation:
      "In the active voice, the subject performs the action expressed by the verb, while in the passive voice, the subject receives the action expressed by the verb." +
      ' In the given sentence, "She makes cakes every Sunday, " the subject "She" is performing the action of making cakes.' +
      " To convert this sentence into the passive voice, we need to make the cakes the subject of the sentence and show that they are being made by her." +
      ' Therefore, the passive form would be "Cakes are made by her every Sunday."' +
      " This form maintains the correct tense (present) and expresses the action in the passive voice.",
  },
  {
    id: 39,
    question:
      " I found this year great Ethiopian run ________________ last years",
    options: [
      "as interested as ",
      " interestinger ",
      " more interesting than ",
      " most interesting of",
    ],
    correct_option: "more interesting than",
    explanation:
      'The correct option is "more interesting than". This option correctly compares the interest level of the Ethiopian run this year to that of last year.' +
      ' The phrase "more interesting than" is used for making comparisons between two things, indicating that one thing is more interesting than the other.',
  },
  {
    id: 40,
    question: "If there __________ a fire, the alarm will ring",
    options: ["is", "was", "will be", "would be"],
    correct_option: "is",
    explanation: ` The correct option is "is". This sentence is in the conditional form, expressing a possibility or condition. In this case, it's stating that if there is a fire, the alarm will ring.`,
  },

  {
    id: 41,
    question: "He always _____________ his home work in the evening.",
    options: ["doesn't do", " doesn't does ", " don't do ", " don't does"],
    correct_option: "doesn't do",
    explanation:
      `The correct form of the verb "do " to use with "he" is "does" in the negative form, resulting in "doesn't do " to indicate that he does not do his homework in the evening.`,
  },
  {
    id: 42,
    question:
      "They ___________ only few fish last night for the weather not conducive.",
    options: ["caught", " catch", " catches ", "catched "],
    correct_option: "caught",
    explanation:
      'The correct past tense form of the verb "catch" is "caught, " so the sentence should be "They caught only a few fish last night for the weather not conducive."',
  },
  {
    id: 43,
    question:
      " What is the interrogative form of ‘Solan celebrated his birthday last week.'",
    options: [
      "Does Solan celebrate his birthday last week? ",
      " Did Solan celebrated his birthday last week?",
      " Do Solan celebrated his birthday last week? ",
      "Did Solan celebrate his birthday last week?",
    ],
    correct_option: "Did Solan celebrate his birthday last week?",
    explanation:
      'To form the interrogative form of a past tense statement, the auxiliary verb "did" is used before the subject, resulting in "Did Solan celebrate his birthday last week ? "',
  },
  {
    id: 44,
    question:
      " While Ahmed ______________ the dining room, he saw a rat under the table.",
    options: ["cleaning ", "cleans", " is cleaning", "was cleaning"],
    correct_option: "was cleaning",
    explanation:
      'The sentence is describing an action that was ongoing (cleaning) at a specific point in the past (while Ahmed saw a rat), requiring the past continuous tense "was cleaning."',
  },
  {
    id: 45,
    question: " He ______________ his phone. He is finding it yet.",
    Options: ["was lost", "is lost ", "has lost", " has been lost "],
    correct_option: "has lost ",
    explanation:
      'The sentence is describing the current state resulting from a past action, requiring the present perfect tense "has lost" to indicate that he lost his phone and is still looking for it.',
  },
  {
    id: 46,
    question: " When you ride a motorbike you__________ wear helmet.",
    options: ["should", " have ", "must", " may "],
    correct_option: "must",
    explanation:
      'The sentence expresses a necessity or obligation when riding a motorbike, indicating that wearing a helmet is mandatory, hence "must" is the appropriate modal verb.',
  },
  {
    id: 47,
    question: " Ras Dashen is___________ mountain in Ethiopia.",
    options: ["the higher", " the highest ", "higher ", " high "],
    correct_option: "the highest",
    explanation:
      'Ras Dashen is being compared with other mountains in Ethiopia, requiring the superlative form "the highest" to indicate it is the highest among them.',
  },

  {
    id: 48,
    question: " . If she__________ on time, she will ________in the class. ",
    options: ["come/get ", " comes/get ", " could/got ", " coming/get "],
    correct_option: "comes/get",
    explanation:
      'The first blank requires the simple present tense "comes" because it is part of the condition for the second part of the sentence,' +
      ' which requires the base form "get" after "will." So, "comes / get" fits both blanks correctly.',
  },
  {
    id: "VI",
    header1: "PART FOUR: COMMUNICATIVE SKILLS",
    header2:
      "Instruction: For questions 44-49 choose the best answer which completes each conversation from the given alternatives",
  },

  {
    id: 49,
    question:
      "Gadisa: I would like to thank you for your being volunteer in this interview. Daniel: ____________________________________________ ",
    options: [
      "I usually like volunteerism work",
      "I come from charity organization",
      "Thank you for giving this chance",
      "I am the member of volunteer organization",
    ],
    correct_option: "Thank you for giving this chance",
    explanation:
      ' Daniel is expressing gratitude for the opportunity given by Gadisa, so the appropriate response is "Thank you for giving this chance.',
  },
  {
    id: 50,
    question:
      "Adane: Would you mind if I tell you something? Surafel: ______________________________; please go ahead ",
    options: [
      "Yes, I do mind ",
      " No, would mind ",
      " Yes of course ",
      "No, I don't mind",
    ],
    correct_option: "No, I don't mind",
    explanation:
      `Surafel is expressing his willingness to hear what Adane has to say, so the response "No, I don't mind" indicates that he is open to it.`,
  },
  {
    id: 51,
    question:
      " . Abera: I can't cope with the life in the countryside so it is bad place; do you agree? Balay: ___________________________________ for me, it so conducive place. ",
    options: [
      "Yes, I strongly agree ",
      " No, I don't have different idea ",
      "No, I strongly disagree",
      " Yes, you are quite right",
    ],
    correct_option: "No, I strongly disagree",
    explanation:
      `Balay is expressing his disagreement with Abera's statement about the countryside being a bad place, indicating that he finds it conducive.`,
  },
  {
    id: 52,
    question:
      " Ayele: The traffic light turns to red what shall I do? Samuel: You ____________ stop driving otherwise you are punished.",
    options: ["should ", "must", " can ", " ought to"],
    correct_option: "must",
    explanation:
      'Samuel is advising Ayele on what action to take when the traffic light turns red, emphasizing the necessity of stopping by using "must."',
  },
  {
    id: 53,
    question:
      " Stranger: Excuse me, can you show me the way to Bethel hospital? Woman: ________________________, go straight then turn to your left. ",
    options: [
      "Why not! ",
      " Yes, Bethel hospital gives good service ",
      "Sorry, I am strange to",
      " Sorry, you are suspicious ",
    ],
    correct_option: "Sorry, I am strange to",
    explanation:
      'The woman is apologizing for her unfamiliarity with the directions, using "Sorry, I am strange to, " which implies she is not familiar with the area.',
  },
  {
    id: 54,
    question:
      "Driver: If you were a farmer, what would you produce? Farmer: ___________________________cash crops.",
    options: [
      "I will produce",
      "I would produce ",
      "I would have produced",
      "I can produce",
    ],
    correct_option: " I would produce ",
    explanation:
      "The farmer is responding to the hypothetical scenario of being a farmer by indicating what he would produce," +
      ' using "I would produce" to express his choice in that situation.',
  },

  {
    id: "VII",
    header1: " PART FIVE: WRITING ",
    header2:
      " Instruction: For questions 55-56, reorganize the jumbled words choose the correct meaningful sentence",
  },
  {
    id: 55,
    question: " Was/cheetah/fast/The/animal/running ",
    options: [
      "The animal running was cheetah fast.",
      " The fast was cheetah running animal.",
      "Cheetah was the fast running animal.",
      "Cheetah animal was fast the running.",
    ],
    correct_option: "Cheetah was the fast running animal ",
    explanation: "",
  },

  {
    id: 56,
    question: " To be/like/a/you/doctor/do",
    options: [
      "You to be a doctor like you? ",
      " A doctor you to like be? ",
      "Do you be a doctor to like?",
      " Do you like to be a doctor?",
    ],
    correct_option: "Do you like to be a doctor?",
    explanation: "",
  },

  {
    id: "IX",
    header1: "Section Three: Punctuation and Capitalization",
    header2:
      " Instruction: For questions 57, read following the jumbled sentences choose the correct order to make a coherent paragraph",
  },
  {
    id: 57,
    question:
      " a. He was a popular physicist. b. He invented law relativity c. Albert Einstein was born in Germany. d. He won Nobel Prize for his invention. ",
    options: ["c, d, a, b ", " a, c, b, d ", "c, a, b, d", " a, d, c, b"],
    correct_option: "c, a, b, d",
    explanation: "",
  },
  {
    id: "X",
    header1: " Section Two: Letter Writing",
    header2:
      " Instruction: Look at the following letter and choose the correct answer for the following questions 58-60 \n" +
      "                       P.O.Box 333 /n" +
      "                     A  Addis Ababa \n" +
      "                     B  October 15,2023 \n" +
      "C  Dear Melon \n" +
      "I am having a birthday party on Sunday, October 19. It will begin at two o'clock. It will be at my house. I hope you can come. \n" +
      "      D Your friend \n" +
      "         Meron",
  },
  {
    id: 58,
    question: " The type of this letter is _______________________",
    options: [
      "S business letter ",
      "personal letter",
      " official letter",
      " job application letter ",
    ],
    correct_option: "personal letter",
    explanation:
      "This letter is informal and is written to invite a friend to a birthday party," +
      "indicating that it's a personal communication rather than a business, official, or job application letter.",
  },
  {
    id: 59,
    question: " Letter D stands for,",
    options: [
      "Sender's address",
      "complimentary closure",
      " body ",
      " the date",
    ],
    correct_option: "complimentary closure",
    explanation:
      ' In a personal letter, the closing part where the sender signs off with their name, like "Your friend, Meron"' +
      " in this case, is considered the complimentary closure.",
  },

  {
    id: 60,
    question: " Letter C stands for, ",
    options: ["Salutation", " heading ", " Body ", "signature "],
    correct_option: "Salutation",
    explanation:
      'In this letter, "Dear Melon" is the salutation, which is the greeting used to address the recipient at the beginning of the letter.',
  },
];
